So, let's start with bagging.
我们先来看一下 bagging
Here's our data in the form of some random blue points.
现在有一些数据 就是图中这些红点和蓝点
And for simplicity, we'll say that
简单起见 我们假设
our weak learners will be the simplest possible learner,
我们要用的弱学习器就是最简单的学习器
a decision tree of one node.
单结点的决策树
So, all of them are either horizontal or a vertical line that says,
也就是说 要么在水平方向上 要么在垂直方向上
"On this side everything is positive,
一侧都是正例样本
and on this side everything is negative."
而另一侧都是反例样本
So, back to our data. Let's do the following.
所以 对这些数据 我们做如下处理
Since our data may be huge,
由于数据可能过于庞大
in general, we don't want to train many models on the same data.
一般来说 我们不想针对同样的数据采用多种模型
This would be very expensive.
这样做代价太大
Instead, we'll just take subsets of it,
相反 我们选取部分子集
and train a weak learner on each one of these subsets.
每个子集使用一种弱学习器
Then, we'll figure out how to combine these learners.
这样我们就知道怎么把这些学习器集合到一起
So, here's our first subset of data,
这是第一个子集
and our first model, our first learner, is this one.
还有我们的第一个模型 也就是第一个学习器
We'll remember this one.
记住这个模式
Now, here's our second subset of data,
这是第二个子集
and our second learner.
和第二个学习器
And if it looks like I'm being too lucky picking my data and my learners, yes, I am.
如果你觉得我这么做看起来很简单 那么确实
In general, these learners can be terrible.
总体来说 这些学习器性能都不好
But, if our data is large enough,
但是 如果我们的数据足够多
picking a random subset normally gives us good intuition on the data,
随机选择一个子集通常就能让我们了解一定情况
plus it makes the process run quickly.
而且能让整个流程进展更快
And finally, our third subset of data,
这是我们的第三个子集
on our third learner,
以及第三个学习器
notice that I never partition that data.
注意 这些数据 我从未做过分区处理
We are completely allowed to repeat points among our subsets,
我们完全可以在子集中复制某些点
and to even not consider some of the points at all.
甚至是忽略某些点
At every step, we pick a fully random subset of data.
每一步 我们都随机选择一个子集
And now, we have three weak learners.
现在 共有三个弱学习器
How do we combine them? Well, what about voting?
我们怎么把它们集合到一起？ 不如通过计票
We overimpose them over the data and say,
我们把这些学习器和点重叠在一起
if two of more of them say blue,
如果数量更多的是蓝点 那结果就是蓝点
then blue, and if two of more of them say red, then red.
如果数量更多的是红点 那结果就是红点
If we have an even number of models,
如果数量持平
we can pick any way we want to break ties.
那么任意选择其中一个即可
Although, with lots of points and lots of models,
尽管在有很多点和模型的时候
it's hard to imagine that we'd get a tie somewhere. It may happen, though.
很难出现数量持平的情况 但这种情况也会发生
And voila, this is what we obtain when we make the models vote.
看 采用计票方式我们就得到了这样的结果
So, that's it. That's the bagging algorithm.
这就是 bagging 算法